Hi.
I'm Travis Corpering and here we are at Carolina Beach Recreation Center and I'm about to teach you how to tomahawk dunk a basketball.
Now, first of all, you want to actually be able to dunk before you get into trying to do anything complex or fancy.
But, if you're already at that level and you're ready to move on up to the next level, here's how you get started.
What you want to do is, you want to take off, just like a regular dunk, 45 feet out and once you take off, you want to raise up and actually bring the ball behind your head.
Bringing the ball behind your head actually can be effective during the game.
A tomahawk can actually be effective during the game if you're trying to dunk and finish strong on somebody underneath the basket, because bringing the ball back makes them have to actually reach for the ball.
You're more prone to get a foul call and complete the dunk.
So, you want to bring it up behind your back.
Touch your numbers if you can and bring it down over the rim with authority so that no one can block your shot.
The harder you bring it down, the less likely they're going to be willing to try it again.
So, try that tomahawk dunk.
Finish it with authority the first time, so the next time you come into paint, they'll have second thoughts.
There you have it -- the tomahawk dunk.